# JOINICHULEADDISON

# JOINICHOLEADDISON UX/UI DESIGNER

## **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

UX/UI designer with a background in Graphic Design and Fashion Design, trained at Georgia Institute of Technology UX/UI bootcamp and graduated from Pratt Institute with a B.F.A. in Communication Design. In previous roles led teams in completing fashion lines, designing graphics, embellishments, websites, photo shoots, email campaigns, and social media content. Specializes in creating design solutions based on user needs, user research, usability tests, information architecture, and interactive design. With an aim to create a functional design that positively impacts users and benefits brands.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

ADSTRACT DESIGN STUDIO, Freelance Designer & Production (July 2012 - Present)

- Help clients create the perfect promotional items for their company or events. Items include but are not limited to silk screened t-shirts and/ or uniforms, embroidery t-shirts or uniforms, flyers, banners, business cards and more.
- · Basic graphic design in Adobe Illustrator.
- · Work directly with silk screen printers, embroidery, and printers to make products.
- · Make embroidery and silkscreen charts for easy production.

#### BILLIONAIRE MAFIA, Head of Design and Merchandising (April 2010 - July 2012)

- Responsible for the conceptual development of product lines from samples through production with style and cost effectiveness.
- Work with Production and overseas factories (China, India, Pakistan) to maintain line quality and create new development.
- · Work with the President, CEO and Sales to create a line for upcoming events and markets.
- Create and oversee the development of Denim, Wovens, Jackets, Vests & Knits for three in house lines, from concept through production with scope and complex judgment for Design. Color. Art and Fit.
- Task manage & work with Art, Design, Sales, Management and Production Department to create new development and maintain line quality.
- Conduct market research for trend forecasting for upcoming seasons.
- Produce quality Designs, Art, Cads and Tech Packs, in a timely manner.
- Managed a design team of 5 people, and effectively inspired teamwork from all members.

# ZIPWAY, Head of Design and Merchandising (September 2008 - April 2010)

- $\bullet$  Responsible for the conceptual development of product lines from samples through production with style and cost effectiveness.
- Work with Production and overseas factories (China, India, Pakistan) to maintain line quality and create new development.
- · Create and oversee Cads, B.O.Ms, Art and Tech Packs.
- Work with the President, CEO and Sales to create a line for upcoming events and markets.
- Create and oversee the development of sweatsuits, track jackets and shorts for two in-house lines, from concept through production with scope and complex judgment for Design, Color, Art and Fit.
- Work directly with NBA teams on Zipway licensed products for the NBA teams.
- Oversee all products from Zipway kids licensee Kids Headquarters.

#### SEAN JOHN, Knitwear and Sweater Designer (January 2005 - April 2008)

- Provide detail sketches and tech packs
- · Hand-off tech packs and development package according to line plan to production team
- Work directly with production team to finalize product and details
- · Responsible for research for fabrics, trims, new art techniques, and fits
- Participate in fittings
- Travel for development and research
- · Organize sales books
- · Create overviews

#### **INFO**

960 East Paces Ferry Rd NE #358 Atlanta, GA, 30326 917-627-9416 joi@joiaddison.com www.joiaddison.com www.linkedin.com/in/joi-addison

#### **EDUCATION**

#### GEORGIA INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY

Atlanta, GA UX/UI Design Certificate complete September 2022

#### PRATT INSTITUTE

Brooklyn, NY B.F.A. in Communication Design graduated *May 2004* 

#### DESIGN AND ARCHITECTURE SENIOR HIGH

Miami, FL

High School Degree Graphic Design major graduated 2000

#### **SKILLS**

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS:**

Figma Invision

HTML CSS

JavaScript

Adobe Creative Suite

Miro

Word

Excel

## UX/UI SKILLS:

Design Thinking
Low to High Fidelity Design & Prototyping
Storyboarding Wireframing
User Research
Usability Testing
Decision Mapping
Flow Diagrams
User Interviews

**UX/UI DESIGNER**